Hi guys!
I'm going to show you how to slice your chicken for the chicken enchiladas.
You want to open them up out of their foil here.
As far as the chicken goes, you want to use a nice sharp knife like this; it's a chef's knife.
You want to keep your tip down over here and you want to just slice across just like that.
You want to make thin slices as thin as possible.
The reason why you want them so thin is so that it's easier to eat and you'll have a lot more pieces to fill your enchiladas.
These chicken enchiladas are not about the chicken or it's not about the beef and it's not about over filling.
You don't want to over fill your enchiladas.
You just want to basically lightly fill them up.
As you can see, I got really nicely thin pieces here that are super thin; a lot thinner than your average fajita.
You just want to slice down at an angle basically.
Keep your tip down.
Make sure not to cut yourself.
Since the chicken has been sitting in the foil, it has nicely cooled down.
You want to make sure to work with cool chicken.
That way you don't burn yourself.
Sooner or later this chicken is going to get a lot hotter when it goes into the oven, so don't worry about it being cool.
You want to keep on slicing all the way through.
Like I said, at an angle until you get nice thin little pieces of chicken.
Now that we have them sliced up into thin slices like I showed you earlier, what you want to do is you want to go and slice the opposite way.
That way we can make little pieces of chicken and it's kind of like shredded chicken.
If you want to chop even more, you can.
You can just chop and chop that way it's kind of like shredded chicken and you'll have these big chunks of chicken inside your enchiladas.
Like I said, it's not about the big thick piece of beef or chicken inside your enchilada.
Enchiladas are not meant to be filled to the max with big pieces of meat or pounds and pounds of cheese.
That is it on slicing and dicing your chicken.